Tom Zmyslo

Senior Software Engineer

269.823.2295
tom@zmyslo.com
www.zmyslo.com
github.com/tomzmyslo

Senior Software Engineer with over a decade of experience developing for the web, mobile and desktop. Values convention over configuration, pushing envelopes, and working smarter, not harder. Well-versed in the full software development lifecycle, from inception to development to production deployment.

Experience

Telus Agriculture & Consumer Goods

Senior Software Engineer

July 2022 - Present

- · Helped define architecture for next-gen Rebate Management product
- · Created new API-only Rails application for next-gen Rebate product
- Manage code deployments to stage and production environments
- Migrated CI/CD pipelines to GitHub Actions

Software Engineer

Oct 2019 - June 2022

- Develop new features for custom Rebate Management product
- Update Ruby-based APIs to support multi-tenancy
- Created a JSON transform pipeline using the jq language
- Develop CQRS-based microservice components in Ruby

Red Ventures

Front End Developer

Oct 2018 - Sept 2019

- Developed React components for a site-wide design system
- Implemented A/B testing scenarios developed by business team
- Integrated a proprietary analytics system
- Participated on the internal Tech Training Team

deZignwright

Lead Developer

Aug 2009 - Dec 2017

- Developed bespoke web applications with Ruby on Rails
- Developed iOS and macOS applications
- Lead application architecture design sessions
- · Managed on-premise servers and network infrastructure
- Routinely communicated directly with clients

Multimedia Specialist

Aug 2007 - July 2009

- Created new media assets for web and disc-based delivery
- Shot, directed, and edited client training videos
- Developed Keynote and PowerPoint presentations

Graphic Designer

Nov 2006 - July 2007

- · Created and updated print assets from brochures to catalogs
- · Adhered to style and brand guidelines

Skills

Areas of Expertise

Agile Methodologies, API
Design, Attention to Detail,
Information Architecture,
Troubleshooting, User
Experience

Programming Languages

Ruby, JavaScript, Swift, CSS, HTML, SQL

Libraries & Frameworks

Ruby on Rails, React, Next.js, Tailwind, SwiftUI, Bootstrap, Node, RSpec

Platforms & Tools

GitHub, Heroku, AWS, Xcode, Docker, Redis, Vercel, Vite

Education

Kalamazoo Valley Community College

Kalamazoo, MI Graphic Design

Western Michigan University

Kalamazoo, MI Business

Berklee College of Music

Boston, MA Music